window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Engineering_Mathematics - Engineering_Mathematics — Slot 2 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Engineering_Mathematics — Slot 2",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Let \\( A=\\begin{bmatrix}\n1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp;4 \\\\\n4&amp;  1&amp; 2 &amp;3 \\\\\n3&amp; 4 &amp; 1 &amp;2 \\\\\n2 &amp;3  &amp;4  &amp;1\n\\end{bmatrix}\\) and \\( B=\\begin{bmatrix}\n3&amp; 4 &amp; 1 &amp;2 \\\\\n4&amp;  1&amp; 2 &amp;3 \\\\\n1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3 &amp;4 \\\\\n2 &amp;3  &amp;4  &amp;1\n\\end{bmatrix}\\)<br>Let det(A) and det(B) denote the determinants of the matrices A and B,\nrespectively.<br>\nWhich one of the options given below is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2023)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>det(A) = det(B)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>det(B) = - det(A)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>det(A)=0</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>det(AB) = det(A) + det(B)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>det(B) = - det(A)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/399304/gate-cse-2023-question-8#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following is/are the eigenvector(s) for the matrix given below?<br>\\( \\begin{pmatrix}\n-9 &amp;-6  &amp;-2  &amp;-4  \\\\\n-8&amp; -6 &amp; -3 &amp; -1 \\\\\n20 &amp; 15 &amp; 8 &amp; 5 \\\\\n32&amp;  21&amp;  7&amp;12\n\\end{pmatrix}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "multiple",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n-1\\\\\n1\\\\\n0\\\\\n1\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n1\\\\\n0\\\\\n-1\\\\\n0\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n-1\\\\\n0\\\\\n2\\\\\n2\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n0\\\\\n1\\\\\n-3\\\\\n0\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n-1\\\\\n1\\\\\n0\\\\\n1\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n-1\\\\\n0\\\\\n2\\\\\n2\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\begin{pmatrix}\n0\\\\\n1\\\\\n-3\\\\\n0\n\\end{pmatrix}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371893/Gate-cse-2022-question-43#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider solving the following system of simultaneous equations using LU decomposition.<br>\\( \\begin{aligned}\nx_1+x_2-2x_3&amp;=4 \\\\\nx_1+3x_2-x_3&amp;=7 \\\\\n2x_1+x_2-5x_3&amp;=7\n\\end{aligned}\\)<br>where L and U are denoted as<br>\\(L= \\begin{bmatrix}\nL_{11} &amp; 0 &amp; 0 \\\\\nL_{21}&amp; L_{22} &amp; 0 \\\\\nL_{31} &amp; L_{32} &amp; L_{33}\n\\end{bmatrix}, U= \\begin{bmatrix}\nU_{11} &amp; U_{12} &amp; U_{13} \\\\\n0&amp; U_{22} &amp; U_{23} \\\\\n0 &amp; 0 &amp; U_{33}\n\\end{bmatrix}\\)<br>Which one of the following is the correct combination of values for \\(L32, U33,\\) and \\(x_1\\)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(L_{32}=2,U_{33}=-\\frac{1}{2},x_1=-1\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(L_{32}=2,U_{33}=2,x_1=-1\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(L_{32}=-\\frac{1}{2},U_{33}=2,x_1=0\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L_{32}=-\\frac{1}{2},U_{33}=-\\frac{1}{2},x_1=0\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L_{32}=-\\frac{1}{2},U_{33}=-\\frac{1}{2},x_1=0\\)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371901/Gate-cse-2022-question-35#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>The value of the following limit is _____<br>\\( \\lim_{x  \\to 0+} \\frac{ \\sqrt{x}}{1-e^{2 \\sqrt{x}}}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "-0.5",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371912/Gate-cse-2022-question-24#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following two statements with respect to the matrices \\(A_{m  \\times n},B_{n  \\times m},C_{n  \\times n}  \\text{ and }D_{n  \\times n},\\)<br><br> Statement 1: \\(tr(AB) = tr(BA)\\)  <br> Statement 2: \\(tr(CD) = tr(DC)\\)  <br><br>where\\(tr()\\) represents the trace of a matrix. Which one of the following holds? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Statement 1 is correct and Statement 2 is wrong.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Statement 1 is wrong and Statement 2 is correct.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both Statement 1 and Statement 2 are correct.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Both Statement 1 and Statement 2 are wrong.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Both Statement 1 and Statement 2 are correct.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371926/Gate-cse-2022-question-10#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>For two n-dimensional real vectors \\(P\\) and \\(Q\\), the operation \\(s(P,Q)\\) is defined as follows:\n<br><br>\n\\(s(P,Q) = \\displaystyle \\sum_{i=1}^n (P[i] \\cdot Q[i])\\)\n<br><br>Let \\(\\mathcal{L}\\) be a set of 10-dimensional non-zero real vectors such that for every pair of distinct vectors \\(P,Q \\in \\mathcal{L}, s(P,Q)=0\\). What is the maximum cardinality possible for the set \\(\\mathcal{L}\\)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>9</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>10</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>11</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>100</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>10</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357503/gate-cse-2021-set-2-question-37#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that \\(f: \\mathbb{R} \\rightarrow \\mathbb{R}\\) is a continuous function on the interval [-3,3] and a differentiable function in the interval (-3,3) such that for every \\(x\\) in the interval, \\(f'(x) \\leq 2\\). If \\(f(-3) =7\\), then \\(f(3) \\) is at most __________ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "19",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357515/gate-cse-2021-set-2-question-25#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that P is a 4x5 matrix such that every solution of the equation Px=0 is a scalar multiple of \\(\\begin{bmatrix} 2 &amp; 5 &amp; 4 &amp;3 &amp; 1 \\end{bmatrix}^T\\). The rank of P is _______ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "4",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357516/gate-cse-2021-set-2-question-24#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following matrix.<br>\\(\\begin{pmatrix} 0 &amp; 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1\\\\ 1&amp; 0&amp; 1 &amp; 1\\\\ 1&amp; 1 &amp; 0 &amp; 1 \\\\1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 0 \\end{pmatrix}\\)<br>The largest eigenvalue of the above matrix is __________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "3",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357399/gate-cse-2021-set-1-question-52#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following expression.<br>\\(\\lim_{x\\rightarrow-3}\\frac{\\sqrt{2x+22}-4}{x+3}\\)\n<br>\nThe value of the above expression (rounded to 2 decimal places) is ___________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2021 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "0.25",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/357431/gate-cse-2021-set-1-question-20#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>If \\(x+2 y=30\\),then \\(\\left(\\frac{2 y}{5}+\\frac{x}{3}\\right)+\\left(\\frac{x}{5}+\\frac{2 y}{3}\\right)\\) will be equal to <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>8</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>16</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>18</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>20</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>16</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331481/isro2020-55\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Let A and B be two nxn matrices over real numbers. Let rank(M) and det(M) denote the rank and determinant of a matrix M, respectively. Consider the following statements. <br><br>\nI.    rank(AB)=rank (A)rank (B)<br>\nII.  det(AB)=det(A)det(B)<br>\nIII. rank(A+B) \\(\\leq\\) rank (A) + rank (B)<br>\nIV. det(A+B) \\(\\leq\\) det(A) + det(B)<br><br>\nWhich of the above statements are TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I and II only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I and IV only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>II and III only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>III and IV only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>II and III only</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/333204/gate2020-cs-27#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Consider the functions <br><br>I. \\(e^{-x}\\) <br>II. \\(x^2-\\sin x\\) <br>III. \\(\\sqrt{x^3+1}\\) <br> <br>\nWhich of the above functions is/are increasing everywhere in  [0,1] ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>III only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>II only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>II and III only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>I and III only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>III only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/333230/gate2020-cs-1#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following matrix:  <br>\\(\\begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 4 &amp; 8\\\\ 1&amp; 3 &amp; 9 &amp;27 \\\\ 1 &amp; 4 &amp; 16 &amp;64 \\\\ 1 &amp; 5 &amp; 25 &amp;125 \\end{bmatrix}\\)<br> The absolute value of the product of Eigenvalues of R is _________ . <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2019)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "12",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/302804/gate2019-cs-44#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>The value of \\(3^{51} \\;mod \\;5\\) is _____ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2019)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "2",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/302827/gate2019-cs-21#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
